Guide to the Earle Ludgin papers, 1920-1979 and undated RL.11586
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Earle Ludgin papers
1920-1979 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Ludgin, Earle, 1898-1981
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11586
4.5 Linear Feet
Advertising executive, founder of Earle Ludgin and Company agency, Chicago, Ill. Collection includes correspondence, clippings, tear sheets and proofs of print advertisements, speeches and other printed materials. Companies represented include: Albert Pick, B. Altman, Bluebird Diamond Syndicate, Chicago Title and Trust, Clinton Carpets (Ozite), Elgin, Elizabeth Arden, Eureka, Lenox, Lucien Lelong, Macy's, Matson Line, Mullins Manufacturing, Pennsylvania Railroad, Rit Dye, Saks, Scott Radio Laboratories, Swift, Walgreen, and W.F. McLaughlin. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: General Files; Earle Ludgin & Company Files.
Biographical / Historical
Advertising executive, founder of Earle Ludgin and Company agency, Chicago, Ill.; Born 1898; attended University of Chicago; Assistant Advertising Manager, Albert Pick Co.; Partner, Paul Floring Industrial Agency; founder, President and Chairman of the Board, Earle Ludgin & Company 1927-; died 1981
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Earle Ludgin papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2017.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Bates Worldwide, Inc. records
Gary P. and Sandra G. Baden Collection of Print Advertisements
J. Walter Thompson Company. 35mm Microfilm Proofs
Margaret Fishback papers
Collection Overview
Collection includes correspondence, clippings, tear sheets and proofs of print advertisements, speeches and other printed materials. Companies represented include: Albert Pick, B. Altman, Bluebird Diamond Syndicate, Chicago Title and Trust, Clinton Carpets (Ozite), Elgin, Elizabeth Arden, Eureka, Lenox, Lucien Lelong, Macy's, Matson Line, Mullins Manufacturing, Pennsylvania Railroad, Rit Dye, Saks, Scott Radio Laboratories, Swift, Walgreen, and W.F. McLaughlin. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising executives -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Macy's (Firm); Pennsylvania Railroad; Elizabeth Arden, Inc.; Swift & Company
- General Files, 1920-1979 and undated; 1
  - Automobile Club of Western Washington, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Biographical sketch, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Cartoon--Les Pas Bleus, undated (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1920 and undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence--David Watrous, 1966-1976 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence--John Willmarth, 1963-1971 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence--Mason Hulett, 1934-1942 (Box 1)
  - Ludgin & Salinger, 1926-1928 (Box 1)
  - Meetings--AAAA Eastern Conference, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Meetings--AAAA Pacific Council, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Meetings--Advertising workshop, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Meetings--Commercial Club of Chicago, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Meetings--Post-Graduate Conference on Advertising That Sells, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Meetings--TV Pioneer dinner, 1954 (Box 1)
  - R.R. Donnelley & Son--New Specimens of Donnelley Deeptone, undated (Box 6)
  - Speeches, 1951-1953; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Speeches, 1954-1963; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Speeches binder, 1951-1958 (Box 2)
  - Stern Walters/Earle Ludgin merger announcement, 1976 (Box 2)
- Earle Ludgin & Company, 1924-1974 and undated; 2
  - General Files, 1931-1974 and undated; 1
    - 10th anniversary, 1937 (Box 2)
    - 25th anniversary, 1952 (Box 2)
    - Advertisements specimen file, 1931-1940 and undated (Box 2)
    - Advertisements specimen file (Not clear if all ads are by Ludgin), 1928-1947 (Box 7)
    - Articles of Co-Partnership, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Chairman of the Board, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
    - Executive Committee Minutes, 1964-1967 (Box 2)
    - Executive Committee Minutes, 1967-1974; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - House advertisements, 1952-1962 and undated; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - House advertisements, 1932-1960 (Box 6)
    - House advertisements, 1951 (Box 7)
    - Press and publicity, 1931-1961; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Press and publicity, 1941-1963; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Vincent Bliss, 1959-1965 (Box 3)
  - Client Files, 1924-1960 and undated; 2
    - Albert Pick Co., 1924-1933 (Box 4)
    - Albert Pick Co. (Pick-Barth), circa 1933 (Box 6)
    - B. Altman, 1937 (Box 7)
    - Bluebird Diamond Syndicate, 1931 and undated (Box 6)
    - Chicago Title and Trust Company, 1941 (Box 6)
    - Chicago Title and Trust Company, 1941-1943 and undated; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Clinton Carpet Company (Ozite), 1928-1937 and undated; 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Clinton Carpet Company (Ozite), 1924-1935 and undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Clinton Carpet Company (Ozite), undated (Box 7)
    - Clinton Carpet Company (Ozite)--A Five Inch Shelf of Books for Hotel Men, undated (Box 5)
    - Clinton Carpet Company (Ozite)--A Partial Roll Call of Users of Ozite Carpet Cushion: Is Your Hotel Listed Here?, rolled mailing, undated (Box 5)
    - Clinton Carpet Company (Ozite)--Down Where Luxury Begins, rolled mailing, undated (Box 5)
    - Clinton Carpet Company (Ozite)--In China, It Is an Ancient Custom to Pay Physicians for Keeping Patients Well, rolled mailing, undated (Box 5)
    - Clinton Carpet Company (Ozite)--In India, The Sacred Tree Is a Symbol of Long Life, rolled mailing, undated (Box 5)
    - E.H. Scott Radio Laboratories, 1941 and undated; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - E.H. Scott Radio Laboratories, 1941-1943 (Box 6)
    - E.H. Scott Radio Laboratories, 1940 and undated (Box 7)
    - Electric Household Utilities Corporation (Hurley Machine--Thor), 1943 (Box 6)
    - Elgin, undated (Box 4)
    - Eureka Williams, 1961 (Box 6)
    - Koolox, undated (Box 4)
    - Lucien LeLong, 1936-1937 and undated; 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Lucien LeLong, 1932-1937 (Box 6)
    - Lucien LeLong, 1937 and undated; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Lucien LeLong "Cooling Cologne" mailer, undated (Box 5)
    - Madison & Kedzie State Bank, undated (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous print advertisements, 1944-1947 (Box 4)
    - Mullins Manufacturing, undated (Box 4)
    - Mullins Manufacturing, 1928-1929 (Box 6)
    - Mullins Manufacturing, 1928 (Box 7)
    - National Association of Glue Manufacturers, 1932 (Box 4)
    - Orphans of the Storm, undated (Box 4)
    - Rit Dye, 1936-1938 (Box 4)
    - Rit Dye, 1934-1937 and undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Rit Dye, 1934-1935 (Box 7)
    - Rostone, undated (Box 4)
    - Sawyer Biscuit Company, circa 1944 (Box 6)
    - Swift & Co., undated (Box 4)
    - Union Tank Car Companies, 1960 (Box 4)
    - W.F. McLaughlin (Coffee), undated, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - W.F. McLaughlin (Coffee), undated, 1933 (Box 7)
    - Walgreen, undated (Box 4)